As the amount of software in the world
increases, there's going to be lots of
problems. There's going to be lots of
things that don't work. There's going to
be lots of edge cases. And like the
difference between those two things is
where I think traditional software
engineering developers will add a huge
amount of value because that gap is
going to change. The way to use AI tools
today, 3 months ago was different and 3
months before that was different. It's
mostly if you want to get the like
frontier level productivity gains, you
need to sort of continue to evolve. The
rules are being rewritten under our feet
and you can either sort of like ride the
wave or you're not going to get these
like frontier level productivity gains.
>> A couple of years ago, you asked how
long until AGI and Musk replied, "Next
year." That didn't happen. Where do you
feel like we are today versus a year ago
on the path to AGI?
>> We're sort of like close to what folks
will feel as this like narrow
superintelligence. I think it's like
actually more close to the way of
describing it. Like if you could have a
model or a system that could like build
anything with code, I think about that
as like narrow superintelligence. AGI is
not going to be a model. It's going to
be a product that somebody creates.
>> Who's down for building that then? Is
that one company, one individual, or is
that more a combination from an
ecosystem of products?
>> That's a good question. I think
>> [music]
[music]
>> Back in November, we hosted the first
ever in-person AI native dev [music] con
in New York. This June 1st and 2nd,
we're bringing it to London. It's 2 days
built for AI native developers and
engineering [music] teams. One day full
of hands-on workshops and one day full
of practical talks on agent skills,
[music] contact engineering, agent
orchestration and enablement platforms,
and how teams are actually shipping AI
in production.
Join us at the brewery in London near
the Barbican [music] for all of that
plus networking, parties, giveaways, and
a room full of people building the
future of AI native development. You can
also join us from anywhere in the world
by the live stream.
As you're listening to this podcast,
[music] you get 30% off your ticket with
code pod30. Just head to
ainativedevcon.io
and we'll see you in London.
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the AI native dev. And we have a special
episode today. We actually have Logan
Kilpatrick from Google DeepMind joining
us today.
Um Logan, a massive thank you and
welcome to the episode. How are you?
>> I'm hanging in there. Lots of uh it's
another week of chaos in the AI
ecosystem. So uh trying to trying to
stay on top of it all.
>> There have been wildfires all over
Twitter and and the social spaces
already this week, haven't they? It's
been It's been quite the quite the ride.
And uh for those listening, it's it's
April 1st today.
Uh but uh but this is the this is the
the the the week in which uh Anthropic
uh
knowingly or unknowingly open sourced uh
Claude code and and and things like
that. So lot lots of fun things
happening happening in the world right
now. Uh Logan, for those of you who
don't know Logan, Logan was uh
previously a leader of the developer
relations team at OpenAI and currently a
member of the technical staff at Google
DeepMind. So Logan, why don't you tell
us a little bit about I guess some of
your time at OpenAI and and moving over
to Google uh and what your day-to-day
looks like?
>> Yeah, it's uh there's lots of parallels.
I do think the ecosystem has changed so
much. I've been at Google
um actually today's my 2-year
anniversary at Google, which is crazy.
>> Yeah, thank you. I joined OpenAI uh end
of 2022 a week after ChatGPT had
launched and sort of got to launch GPT-4
and ship a bunch of, you know, the chat
completions API, the assistants API,
plugins, GPTs, a bunch of other stuff
across the ecosystem.
Um
and just seeing how
how fast things have changed um and how
much progress we've made. I think like
my most interesting reaction is like,
you know, all the agent stuff 12 months
ago, there was like lots of
conversations about agents in the
developer ecosystem and and more broadly
and like to see them actually work now
and like people are building agentic
products, people are using agents to
like do the things that it was sort of
like the promise. And it's it's
interesting to see this and we should
talk more about it because like it was
kind of like a joke 12 months ago. It
was like, oh, you're doing agents like
hahaha, like that doesn't really work.
It's kind of science fiction. I think
today it's like very real. And so I'm
always thinking about like what are
those next set of things and and so
spend a lot of time like with our team
thinking about like what are those next
set of things that we need to be
thinking about that are sort of
a little bit science fiction today. My
like uh, we have a bunch of these like
research to reality uh, monikers
internally that we sort of like think
about of how we it's our team's
responsibility to bridge the research to
reality um, because we sit in a research
org inside of DeepMind and our job is to
build products for for builders and
developers. So, um, the day-to-day looks
like shipping products and shipping
features and building a platform so that
we can make that research to reality
flywheel happen.
>> We'll start off with the today and then
we'll kind of like lean into the
tomorrow at towards the end of the
episode. Um, so so one of the super
interesting pieces that have come out of
Google recently is is AI Studio. Um, and
of course many of already familiar with
you know, more of the the terminal UI
style of using using uh, Gemini and
things like this. So, first of all, talk
us through a little bit about what AI
Studio is and why people would maybe
lean into AI Studio more than Gemini and
when people would kind of like more lean
into the into the terminal versus the
UI.
>> Yeah, it's a great question. I think one
of the one of the beauties and one of
the challenges of Google is that like we
have a very wide ecosystem. We're sort
of touching every part of the developer
life cycle. We're touching every part of
uh, the different ecosystems across like
web and mobile and cloud etc. etc. AI
Studio I think the most simple way to
frame it is is a platform, a set of
things that help you go from prompt to
prototype to production and do that
really fast using all of our AI
infrastructure.
So historically AI Studio was like a UI
playground that you could sort of test
all of Google DeepMind's latest models
and experiment with them
and then actually take them into the API
and like go and build products and and
tools and apps on top of the Gemini API.
And I think what's happened in the last
6 months is we've sort of continued to
evolve the platform. We still have that
playground functionality so you can test
all the latest models on day one and and
sort of experiment with them. We also
now have an entire vibe coding
experience and I think part of this is
like
it's a natural extension of the work
that we were doing with the playground
which is like help people understand how
to actually get these models into
products
and like bring their ideas to life. I
think the main thing that's also shifted
is like there's just way more people
now. It's not just developers, it's this
sort of like next gen developer builder
persona who
historically couldn't use these tools
who now can and I think it's part of our
mission in AI Studio and probably inside
of DeepMind is to like bring this
technology to as many people as
possible. So now you can go to
ai.studio/build you can like vibe code
entire apps that are built on top of you
know
Firebase which is our sort of like
storage solution
and parts of Google you can deploy using
Cloud Run, you can sort of use Google
Search, you can have grounding data with
Google Maps and sort of we're exposing
all these bits of the Google ecosystem
and and lots more cool stuff coming on
that front
in a way that's just simple. You can
click a couple of buttons, you don't
need to sign up for eight different
accounts and we're sort of like bringing
together the ecosystem and building this
platform for people to build on top of
which has It's really really exciting.
So lots of lots of cool things. To
answer the question specifically, like
Gemini the app versus AI Studio and like
Gemini CLI versus AI Studio and then
even anti-gravity versus AI Studio,
um Gemini app is sort of like a personal
assistant for your everyday use. Um so,
like, you know, I was asking a bunch of
medical questions to the Gemini app this
morning. Um
the Gemini CLI is like a a form factor
of the CLI. So, if you're a developer,
you use CLIs and sort of that feels
native to you. Great product experience
as a developer to go and use that. Um
and then anti-gravity is sort of this
like full-stack IDE agentic developer
platform uh where you can actually go
and and similar to what you would do
inside of like Cursor or Cloud Code,
etc., etc., you can build apps. So, if
you're a developer, it's sort of your
daily driver uh to go and write code in
like really complex code bases, etc.,
etc.
AI Studio sort of has a
batteries-included app builder and then
a bunch of like underlying
infrastructure that folks can build on
top of.
>> And do you think that, you know, a a lot
of this is very kind of um dependent on
how the the the engineer or the
developer wants to work? Some people
prefer to like terminal UI, some people
prefer the more the the the the IDE
approach. Um
there's a version that people believe
where sometimes, you know, vibe coding
is maybe for more for non-developers and
actually, you know, uh senior engineers
don't really need to change the way they
work and things like that. Do you feel
like we will actually converge into into
an an approach whereby if you look at
development today, 99% of develop Well,
not today, sorry, 5 years ago, 99% of
developers were using an IDE to develop.
Today, that's very much more split. Do
you feel like when we get to a stage
where agentic development is just the
norm, we will have a single typical way
where people will develop code? Um or do
you still feel like there will be the
more technical folks that maybe want to
lean into the terminal, other people
will maybe more want a visual aspect.
Are we in a moment in time or do you
think that's going to persist?
>> My assumption is that it will persist
and part of this is like back to the
threat of like personal preference.
Like this has always been the case. Like
there's been developers pre-AI era who
were using IDEs. Like I've I've always
been sort of an IDE user myself. I was
using, you know, VS Code and whatever
the one that was built by GitHub back in
the day that there's another they had
their own GitHub at one point had their
own IDE before like pre-Microsoft
acquisition that I I used a bunch that I
really liked. And at the same time
there's always been like Vim and Emacs
and a bunch of these like more terminal
CLI centric tools. And I think this is
just like a developer comfort thing.
There's like trade-offs from an
ergonomic perspective, there's
trade-offs from a productivity
perspective. I think that will actually
increase with all this stuff. And I
think part of this part of the world
view of this is like
the ability to create new software, the
like cost is going down. So I think
there'll be like even more exploration.
There'll be like even more weird stuff.
Like you could imagine like each
developer actually has this like very
customized experience of like how they
like to build software, how their mental
model like the way I think about
software may be different because we
learned in different languages and we
sort of, you know, you know, come from a
different place or whatever it is. So
you can sort of really customize that.
And I think
I think [clears throat] developers will
actually probably end up building a lot
of this stuff for themselves. I also
think there'll be like platforms that
have this level of extensibility
where like, you know, you could imagine
ever in the future every developer has
like a fork of VS Code for example and
it's like, you know, there's the editor
part of that but then there's an agentic
part of that as well that they sort of
build themselves and customize.
That's maybe like an extreme world view
but I think there's like the answer is
probably something in the middle and I
think you'll see a lot of this like
developer choice, meet people where they
are. All these different ecosystems
require different stuff. People's level
of like comfort and familiarity with AI
and these tooling is also different. So
like it warrants a different product
experience and it's actually hard to
build that
like highly extensible customized
product experience at least today if
you're like one of the teams that are
building this product.
>> Absolutely. I'd love to kind of
go a little bit deeper into the kind of
like the the how we can vibe code well.
So one thing that you mentioned was if
you want 30 things as part of your, you
know, vibe coding task, ask for 30
things in the in the in the first
prompt. The model is now smart enough to
handle that logic. And and that was kind
of like a little bit different to the
original form where we had to
essentially ask for something small and
build up because giving too much
information, too much context
essentially, would would overwhelm that
model. Do we need to rethink the way we
were kind of originally taught to
develop with AI?
>> Yeah, 100%. I think it's not um but my
my framing of this is like
this phenomena is going to continue. So
like you need to have this sort of it's
it's part of the challenge of this
moment and and I fall into this, you
know, the the bucket of the folks who
have a difficulty with this as well. So
I'm not saying that I've figured it out,
but like you need to have the mental
plasticity to sort of like change. The
ecosystem, like the way to use AI tools
today, 3 months ago was different and 3
months before that was different. It's
mostly if you want to get the like
frontier level productivity gains, you
need to sort of continue to evolve. And
that's hard. It's just like difficult as
a human to continue to do that, but like
that is the reality of what needs to
happen. And this like ask for 30 things
um example is like a very acute way of
of
uh feeling the difference. Like truly
for me, 12 months ago I was like, let me
ask for the bare minimum thing possible
because otherwise the model will sort of
and the agent will fumble over itself,
not be able to actually do what I ask.
And now I'm like constantly kicking
myself to be like, maybe I should ask
for three extra things um or four extra
things or five extra things or all 30
things that I want and the rate limit is
now like how quickly can I ask for
things
and that's just a very different world
to be in and I think that it's it's been
like literally in the last 6 months that
this shift has happened. I think it what
this was not the case a year ago. So
yeah, you kind of need to the rules are
being rewritten under our feet and you
you can either sort of like ride the
wave or
um
yeah, or you're not going to get these
like frontier level productivity gains.
>> Yeah, another I guess kind of thing that
has really shown its face here is
context and I think prompt engineering
was a thing which we discussed and
talked about, you know, a couple of
years ago but seems to have died off now
in terms of the importance compared to
something like context engineering and
in particular I guess skills over the
last 6 months or so or less skills have
kind of like
you know, been built up and and used so
heavily by people for productivity
gains. How much do you use or how much
do you hold context and skills
as a part of a real efficiency gain in
the in your work in in AI studio and in
Gemini?
>> Yeah, we have a ton of skills that the
like when I do like engineering work and
use anti-gravity internally to sort of
like build AI studio.
We have a ton of our engineering teams
build like tons of skills which is great
for me because I don't know how every
I'm not a sort of day-to-day engineer at
Google. So I don't know how a lot of the
systems work. So they can bring that
context into the skill and sort of
influence like the architecture
decisions and stuff like that which is
really helpful.
My world view has always been that like
prompt engineering was a bug. Like if
you go and talk to users
they don't want to prompt engineer and
actually like the things that you're
asking them to add in already exist
somewhere else. So like your job as the
human using AI systems and sort of like
the LLM or AI app 1.0 era was like to do
the context engineering. That was the
value add and as like what you were
providing as the human in that
experience was going and finding all
these disparate sources, bringing it
into a little chat box, and then sending
it off to the model so it could do
something useful. I think my worldview
sort of shifted when deep research came
out, which was you could sort of like
take this really ill-formed question or
idea or hypothesis, and you could sort
of send it off to deep research, um and
Gemini would sort of like go and browse
the web and find all the different data
sources and like do this context
engineering on the fly to really sort of
like bring all the information in, and
it was a I had this magic aha moment
where the deep research UI would like
show you all the different like sites it
was visiting and all that you'd see like
hundreds of sites and thousands of sites
even in some cases being visited, and it
just like was the epiphany to me that
like this is clearly the way that the
products are going to end up going,
which is people do the thing that humans
do, which is like we ask our very like
context-thin
questions, comments, requests,
um and then the system actually goes and
does the work in order to go and find
that, and you see that now actually with
coding tools, which is like I can ask
for some change, I'm in a million-line
code base um somewhere in like the model
will then go like grep all the files and
sort of look through and try to find you
know, pull in the right pieces of
context. I don't need to say like and I
think it's sitting in this random HTML
file in this folder here, like that is a
complete bug, you shouldn't have to do
that. Um you should be able to with like
pretty minimal context go and do these
things, and the model should be able to
figure it out. And so I'm I'm very happy
that on the coding side we've like seen
that as the direction of travel, and I
think hopefully we'll see that in like a
bunch of other domains as well. Um but
this is the unlock uh is
the model on the fly doing context
engineering. It's an interesting thread
of skills because they're obviously very
helpful today. Um
I think it will be a similar direction
of travel, which is like the models will
probably learn how to make skills on the
fly and thus
um
not and actually the the reason why this
will end up being the case is because
like it's a token saving efficiency
thing, which is like if you can get some
like really solid skill that has the
right context, it just makes it so that
the the model can figure a bunch of this
stuff out. It is just going to like
fumble its way through. It's going to
like send 100 requests to the Google
Drive API and none of them will work and
it'll sort of like self-correct a bunch
of times and read 20 web pages and look
at 70 examples. It'll figure it out, but
like it just takes a lot of time and it
wastes your it wastes your tokens.
Um
so skills I think in the short term are
like a helpful way to just get around
that, but I would expect over time that
the model just like pre-writes a bunch
of this stuff or pulls from some
repository of like domain authority
skills, whatever it is,
um and then solves this problem so that
like humans aren't handcrafting skills
in the way that I think they are today.
>> Yeah, it's super interesting and I and I
think I I I love the I love the fact
that you called prompt engineering a bug
there and I think that it that's
absolutely the right way of thinking
about it because there really was that
that that disconnect really between
human and and and LLM, whereby typically
it's the human not asking for something
in a way that the LLM really expected,
uh
you know, to be asked about a certain
thing. Context is very interesting cuz I
guess a particular with skills because
the model will maybe not understand or
know exactly how that user or that
developer wants something to be
presented. There could be the average
how the industry works, but it's more
how a company maybe its policies, maybe
it's in you know, very specific things
in a skill. I guess the model can find
that out locally,
um but I I really like your approach
there of saying, you know, it could do
all that research, but if the skills are
just there, they could be handcrafted
once or they could be they could be
built by the LLM, but once they're
there, you might as well kind of like
just have that in some repository and
and just pull that as needed. So, I I
love that approach.
>> I'd I'd love to ask a question actually
about
about when you talked about in a
previous quote where you said software
volume's going to be a million times
what it is now in 10 years. That's both
exciting, amazing, and scary at the same
time.
What what do you feel that's going to do
to the value of development or a
developer? How how's that going to
change when we have to look after and
deal with that much code?
>> Yeah, it's a it's an interesting
question cuz I think like the landscape
is shifting so quickly and so
dynamically. I think there's a few
things like A, in 10 years like what we
consider to be development will likely
look significantly different. There will
still be things that are similar. Like
people will still be
sort of like fixing problems with
software. I don't think that's going to
go away.
I think the way in which the tools are
wielded sort of like the the scope, the
level of detail. I think a lot of those
things are sort of like up in the air in
my head as far as how it's going to
shake out.
The interesting thing is
um
why I'm like relatively
bullish for software engineering or just
like engineering as a discipline in
general is because like
as the amount of software in the world
increases and as the like number of
people who are creating software and
having software created on their behalf
increases, um there's going to be lots
of problems. There's going to be lots of
things that don't work. There's going to
be lots of edge cases. There's going to
be There's always going to be a frontier
of like what can the tools do that like
the average person wielding them can't
do. And like the difference between
those two things is where I think
engineering sort of like traditional
software engineering developers will add
a huge amount of value because there
will that gap is going to change, but
like the gap is also is going to be ever
present. Um even if the even if the
models and the tools get get really
really good. I also think it's like
I think people get caught up [snorts] in
a lot of the like
pedagogy of like this this conversation,
which is like what I think about
software engineering, I think about like
a a way of solving problems, a way of
thinking about the world, a way of like
um
yeah, a a way of approaching problems
and I don't think about it like I'm not
at least
personally myself like attached to this
like I type keys and characters show up
on the screen and then those things
represent, you know, some formal
structured programming language like
Python or JavaScript or whatever. Um I
think it's like more general and
actually if you look at like
computer science education like in a lot
of cases there's like there's a there's
a difference in the way that it's taught
different places, but like there's lots
of computer science education which is
like what I'm talking about which is
just like very problem-solving. It's a
way of thinking about the world. Um AI
doesn't
minimize the value of that. I think it
actually like accelerates the value of
it and that value of like
the way of thinking about the world,
the [clears throat] way of
problem-solving I think is going to be
like super super valuable. Again, I
think the value of like typing a typing
keys
uh that make characters render is
probably going to go down though I still
think there'll be reasons to do that and
there'll be value of it.
Um
but this like way of solving problems I
think is going to persist and like I'm
grateful that I like spent the time to
think about those things and like it
manifests in the way that I build stuff
today.
Um
yeah.
>> Yeah, do you think there's a mechanical
sympathy there essentially in terms of
us understanding how things have been
built to allow us to actually architect
and and and make applications you know,
more reliable, more more robust going
forward?
>> 100%. Yeah, yeah. I think you you
someone needs to have the level of depth
to understand all these things.
Um I think it's like does everyone need
that level of depth? Probably not. But
like you want to have like experts to go
in uh go deep in these different areas
and like think really deeply about the
systems and know the right know the
right questions to ask. Also a lot of it
is like
>> [clears throat]
>> as the as the means to build software is
like dramatically increased like lots of
life and lots of these like technical
decisions don't have a real answer. They
have somebody who has a strong opinion.
Um and so I think you still need
somebody to like have the opinion based
on their own experiences or their sense
of the direction that they're that you
want to go to like make a bunch of these
technical questions. Like there's often
not like a single right technical
direction. There's many possible
technical directions and it's like based
on people's own lived experiences and
intuition and understanding of technical
constraints they make a bunch of
decisions. Um so I think the same thing
will all of that will continue on in the
future.
>> Interesting. Let's continue looking into
the future a little bit and talk a
little bit about uh the wonderful topic
of AGI. Um now a couple of years ago
um you asked uh how this is on Twitter
on X, how long until AGI? And uh and
Musk replied, "Next year." That didn't
happen. And I actually I really like
your kind of your your underneath the
sitting underneath the hype approach to
this. And you said, "Someone is going to
weave together the right components at
the product level with a model that's
really smart and people going to call
that AGI." And I and I and I think
that's really interesting because
obviously the AGI timeline predictions
that you know many have kind of
thrown around haven't really aged that
well. So I guess
where do you feel like first of all we
are today versus a year ago
on the on the path to AGI?
>> I think this conversation has gotten
even more complex over time cuz I think
when a A of these conversations started
a few years ago and like even like 10
years ago like you didn't have tools
that could do any of these things.
Um it was sort of like very it was very
like academic, very philosophical and I
think a lot of the definitions and sort
of like preconceived notions are
grounded in that initial stage where
there wasn't like we didn't have tools
that had any of these capabilities. Um
and or like the most advanced version
was like, you know,
AI playing games um but like it didn't
generalize to a bunch of other things
yet. I think the
the like product adoption and the
tooling and the way that this is
impacting our lives has changed so
dramatically in the last 3 years that
I've almost like decoupled myself from
some of these like AGI conversations
because
uh I think it's important that somebody
has these conversations and like thinks
about it and and sort of like has this
uh more sort of like academically
rigorous point of view. I don't have
that point of view. I think like my
world view is very grounded in I think
how the world how like the average
person is going to interact with this
stuff. If you took the technology we had
today and you brought it 3 years ago,
they'd be like, "Holy crap, you know,
that's the future. That is, you know,
these systems are so smart and can do
everything." So like
in some sense the goal post keeps
moving. Um
in some sense I think we are like, you
know, AI coding is an example of like so
much value being created all these like
research tools, all these other things
like
it feels like
we're sort of like close to what
folks will feel as this like narrow
um
this like narrow superintelligence. I
think is like actually more close to the
way of describing it. Like if you could
have a model or a system that could like
build anything with code, I think about
that as like narrow superintelligence.
Humans can't
compete on the same level in that
respect. Um I think from like the like
academically rigorous point of view,
this like AGI question is grounded in
whether or not the models have the
generality. And so I think they still
don't have generality. Like, you know,
at the same time that I can basically
build anything I want with software
today using AI coding tools, I can trip
the models up with all these like goofy
things that humans are able to really
easily do. And so
I think the academically rigorous
argument is like, well, we don't have
this general intelligence um until we
can not trip until the models don't get
tripped up with these things. Like, you
know, it's pretty easy to beat the
models at poker, chess, or any of these
things that like humans can be
relatively good at.
My worldview is like
for the average person it doesn't
matter. Um for the average person these
tools are super impactful. They're like
already creating tons of economic value.
Um I think like this like system from an
AGI perspective is my worldview of like
AGI is not going to be a model, it's
going to be a
a product that somebody creates.
Um and I think that's already the like
I think folks would probably agree with
this worldview, even those who have this
like very academically rigorous point of
view, just given the way that the models
are, you know, now
to do coding as an example, you need
sort of an agent harness, and you need a
a product, you know, whether it's a CLI
or an IDE to like bring the model to
life. You need all these things. So
like, I think this worldview is like
um likely tracking the progress that
we're making. My last quick comment is I
think it's a realization that like
there's this capability overhang. And so
I think that's part of my worldview of
like why we'll see like it's likely that
it won't be like, and this model lab
just dropped a new model, and then
everyone thinks it's AGI. I think it's
going to be that like there was a model
that came out 3 months ago, some really
smart product and engineering team found
a way to like do something really
interesting with it, and put it into a
system that I think people generally
think is AGI because there's this huge
capability overhang that exists today.
>> And that resonates so strongly with me
because if you think about what's
actually unlocked
you know, development today with AI,
it's not a model that has you know, got
significantly better than any other
model. It's It's the fact that agents
has been has been layered on top of that
and it's that interaction between agents
and and well well as an LLM itself and
agent and a and a and a back-end LLM
that has made agentic development so
much power more powerful. I think that
when you say it's AGI will probably feel
like a product release. It's that
environmental how you actually build
your system that has a various products
in versus a a single LLM that that kind
of like says, "Okay, ask me anything you
want. I'm AGI." It's It's For me that I
That does make sense what you're saying
there as a as a product or a a feeling
really with a set of products in an
environment makes makes a ton more
sense.
If AGI again does arrive kind of more as
a product experience than a single
model, who's who's down for building
that then? Is that Is that one company,
one individual or is that kind of more a
combination from an ecosystem of
products?
>> Yeah, it's a good question. I think this
is one of the interesting threads about
like, you know, I'm grateful
to be at Google because I think we have
product distribution across all these
things
um across like so many different
verticals and and places that uh you
might expect need to be good if we
really were to have this like general
level of intelligence.
Um
So, yeah, I don't know. It'll It'll be
interesting to see. I don't know if I
have the answer. Um
but I would expect like your
you know, the Gemini app as like a as
like a personal assistant sort of like
to help you in your everyday life. I
think should if it's like artificially
uh generally intelligent, um it should
be able to like dispatch and work with
all these different tools and ecosystems
to like help me complete any task that I
want. Um, and I think we're like, you
know, we're trending in that direction
with tool use and all these other things
uh that are like coming to the to the
app. And I think that that paradigm will
continue as you'll likely have this like
um again that product experience where
like one system maybe like relies on
many other systems. Um, but I think it
will be very
I think I think it's under appreciated
probably the level of breadth and depth
and the like complexity of solving this
like artificial general intelligence
thing. Like I would be very surprised if
it's like we end up with this just like
chat UI where you go in and you just ask
your question and everyone's like this
is AGI cuz it can do anything. I think
it's going to probably be this like very
orchestrated like lots of different
stuff. Um, a ton of UI complexity and
all these different things. I I think
it's going to be like much more verbose
than I think this like simple AGI idea
that that um that folks have to That's
at least my personal feeling of of how
things will shake out.
>> Hey everyone. Hope you're enjoying the
episode so far. Our team is working
really hard behind the scenes to bring
you the best guests so we can have the
most informative conversations about
agentic development. Whether that's
talking about the latest tools, the most
efficient workflows, or defining best
practices. But for whatever reason, many
of you have yet to subscribe to the
channel. If you're enjoying the podcast
and want us to continue to bring you the
very best content, please do us a favor
and hit that subscribe button. It really
does make a difference
>> [music]
>> and lets us continue to improve the
quality of our guests and build an even
better product for you.
>> [music]
>> All right, back to the episode. Cool.
Logan, this has been awesome. I want to
jump into some quick fire questions to
to to wrap up this episode. Um, first of
all, and honestly Luke Logan, OpenAI or
Google, where did you have more fun?
>> I'm having more fun at Google these
days. Um I think it's
uh yeah, it's an incredible place to to
build products. So.
>> Awesome. When you were at Open AI, what
was one thing Sam Altman got right that
no one really gives him credit for?
>> I think people give him Sam a lot of
credit for a lot of things. Um I think
he was right about the level of compute.
I think Sam was like maniacally focused
on making sure that they were resource
resourced for the level of like AI
consumption. I think he was he was right
to make that the focus even like you
know, basically the first meeting I was
ever in with Sam, he was talking about
that. So, um he was definitely right
about it.
>> Amazing.
There are a lot of big labs out there
now all jostling for position. If you
had to bet on one lab not existing in 5
years, which one would it be?
>> That's a good question. I think maybe
the the bet would more so be that like
I think the way that we see them as labs
today, I think will be different. So, I
think like one of these labs will likely
evolve into something that like probably
doesn't look like the like lab of
today's era. Uh but I think all of them
have my sense is like there'll be many
winners in the ecosystem, but I think
people will like pivot into different
and there's like a good actually I don't
know if the social media analogy is
perfect, but like a lot of the early
social media products looked very
similar and over time they ended up like
it's very clear to most people that like
Snapchat's a completely different
business and product than Instagram than
you know, X and Twitter is etc. etc. So,
I think we end up in that kind of setup
um a little bit.
>> Awesome.
What would you say is most overrated
today? Agents, rag, or prompt
engineering?
>> I think people have moved on from rag
and prompt engineering. Um so, they they
perhaps were overrated before, but I
feel like they're probably adequately
rated now which is that people don't put
a lot of stock in them. Obviously still
important both from like a conceptual
point of view, but um I think the
frontier has moved on and people are
focused on other things.
>> Sounds good. What is the most overhyped
AI benchmark today?
>> I like SweetBench a lot. Um, I think
that my my only comment on this is like
and there's better versions now and
actually the folks who built SweetBench
have done a great job of like continuing
the a bunch of the different versions of
SweetBench, but some of the original
versions of SweetBench is like
completely out of distribution of like
how I think most people do development
work. It's like
tested. I think there's it's like 40
this could be it's like I'm off on this.
I don't remember the specific numbers,
but it's like 40% of the original
SweetBench is like the model setting up
Django. Um, which is like fine and it's
great that it can measure that, but like
probably out of distribution from like
how developers spend 40% of their time.
Um, so they've done a great job of
continuing to evolve. So I think maybe
not they're overhyped, but uh, they've
done a great job of like meeting the
moment with some of the new SweetBench
stuff that they've that they've done.
>> Yeah.
In 10 years time, will there be more or
fewer software developers than today?
>> I think the absolute number will
probably be very similar and I think
they'll be like new role profiles where
they'll be like maybe 10 to 100 x more
people who are touching code on a daily
basis.
Um, they're probably also just like this
like member of the technical staff
profile is a good example of this.
They're probably just doing other
things. So absolute number of developers
same number of people touching code, I
would expect to be like dramatically
more um, than what it is today.
>> What would you say there are a lot of
amazing research papers over the last
few years. What would you say is the
most important AI paper of the last
couple of years?
>> It's probably scaling laws or the
original transformer paper just sort of
as
um,
yeah, setting up this this industry that
we're in today and those two things have
really held true and had a huge impact.
>> Which AI company would you say is most
underestimated right now?
>> I think people underestimate DeepMind
actually. Um,
I don't I think they're you know, I'm
the I every 6 months I think to myself
is
Google the best place in the world and
to be doing this work and every 6 months
the answer is the same which it is.
I think there's just like so many great
things about being at Google and um
the the like talent and the way sort of
like Demis runs DeepMind I think is all
deeply resonates with me. So um
it's
it's hard that Google's a big ship but
when you steer it in the right direction
things go really well. So I'm I'm
excited.
>> Amazing. And the last question Logan,
what would what's the one thing you wish
developers would stop asking you?
>> I wish they would stop asking
you know, a rate rate limiting stuff
and and I think there's like a there's a
threat of this is not because I feel
I've a lot of empathy for folks asking
this question. I think it is and we're
doing a lot on the product side both on
AI studio and across Google and other
products to like solve this problem like
the future version of the world that I
want is like abundant compute developers
can just do the things that they want
they're not worried about rate limits
and they're not worried about quota
stuff. I think we need to do a bunch of
stuff from a product perspective to make
that possible but so I don't hope I
selfishly hope they stop asking because
we solve this problem not because I'm
annoyed by them asking.
>> That sounds amazing. That's a that's a
future we can definitely live in. Logan
this has been absolutely great fun.
Thank you so so much taking the time out
to to speak with us and
I appreciate it.
>> Thank you for all the thoughtful
questions. This was this was a ton of
fun.
>> Awesome. Thanks everyone for listening
in. Tune in to the next episode soon.
Bye for now.
>> [music]